EZEQUIEL CARDONA

Full-stack developer

MAIN SKILLS

FRONT-END:

- React fundamentals, use of *React hooks*, and creation of custom ones.
- Use of *Redux Toolkit* for global state management.
- Use of react-testing-library for unit and integrational testing.
- Use of design templates like Material UI or Bootstrap, and other style controls like CSS modules or styled components.
- Use of Three. JS for 3D UX.
- UX history tracking and analyzing for constant user flow experience, with tools like Google Analytics and Hotjar
- Solid use of HTML and CSS for rendering FE.
- Use of the main techniques for SEO.

BACK-END:

- Node.js fundamentals. Use of frameworks like Nest.JS or Express.JS, for building RESTful APIs or server-side apps. Authentication, security, and error handling.
- Use of tools like Sequalize for controlling PostgreSQL and Mongoose for MongoDB.
- Use of Docker and Kubernetes for creating, managing, and deploying microservices.
- Unit tests with tools like Nest.js Spec library.
- Use of PHP for building server-side apps.

OTHERS:

- Use ESLint and Typescript for code formatting, and data typing.
- Use of agile methodologies for grooming and implementing product requirements.
- Use of Heroku and Netlify for serving remote applications.
- Use of GIT methodologies for running and maintaining an app at production.

SUMMARY

As a passionate and creative software developer, I have honed my skills and expertise through a variety of experiences. Beginning my career as a freelance web developer, I gained valuable professional communication skills and learned the importance of taking ownership of my work.

As I pursued more technical work, I mastered JavaScript, PHP, and databases, building server-side rendering apps. This led me to specialize in React and front-end development.

Building on this foundation, I joined a leading software consultancy, where I grew into a full-stack JavaScript developer with a focus on React and Node. I am excited to bring my skills and experience to new challenges and opportunities.

PROJECTS

React + Node web app collaborations:

- https://launchpod.agileengine.com. An automation tool for job applicants to run their own process.
- Developer Submission Profile. An intern automation tool for a big software consultant recruitment process.

React + PHP web app creation:

https://ferranelotro.info/website

JavaScript + PHP web app creation:

https://venecambiospana.com

CMS website building, SEO, CRM integration, and data management:

- https://latinadventures.com.ec
- https://sajuthemonkey.com
- https://formacion.grupofusa.org
- https://mappex.com.co
- https://miterapiaenlinea.com

EDUCATION

Degree in Statistical Sciences.

"Universidad de Oriente" March 2018 - 5th semester approved. (Course frozen).

High School diploma.

U.E "Nuestra Señora de la Asunción" July 2016 - Bachelor in sciences.

PERSONAL INFO

Nationality: Venezuelan.

Age: 24 years old.

Residence: Medellín, Colombia.

CONTACT INFO

Phone: +57 313 2753083.

Email: ezequiel 98.08.27@gmail.com LinkedIn: Ezequiel Cardona Márquez

EXPERIENCES

Agile Engine, React Engineer

Jan. 2022 - Jan. 2023

- Worked as a React engineer covering all phases of a front-end structure.
- Designed and implemented UX proposals into front-end structures.
- Covered full-stack functionality implementations with a back-end architecture already built.
- Groomed functionalities and implemented them as the owner of user stories.
- Participated in stakeholders' meetings as the face of the developer team.

VeneCambiosPana, Full-stack developer

Jan. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Designed an automation tool for the business model, that saved steps for both business operators and clients.
- · GIT and deployment maintenance.
- Client/stakeholder dev bridge.

Freelancer, Full-stack developer

Feb. 2019 - Jan. 2021

- Worked on multiple projects including a CMS written in JS with React, PHP, and MySql, responsive websites for e-commerce, and singlepage applications.
- Developed communication and ownership to a solid level in the nitch of web applications.

THANK YOU!